Guide to the Ricardo Sánchez Papers, 1941-1995
Department of Special Collections
- SERIES II: Correspondence, c. 1962-1994.
  - Subseries #1. General correspondence
    - Eger, Ernestina (1978) (Box 23, Folder 4)
      Prospectus: A Bibliography of Criticism of Contemporary Chicano Literature
    - El Paso Arts Resources Department (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - El Paso Community College (1975, 1989-1991) (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - El Paso Guidance Center (1989) (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - El Paso Herald Post (1988-1989) (Box 23, Folder 8)
      Joe Olvera (?) Charles Edgren
    - El Paso High School (1987) (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - El Paso Hispanic Chamber of Commerce (1989-1991) (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - El Paso Public Library (1989) (Box 23, Folder 11)
      Sánchez Papers Collection
    - El Paso Public Library (1993) (Box 23, Folder 12)
      1994 Centenial Celebration
    - El Paso Public Television Foundation (1983) (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - El Paso Times (1989) (Box 23, Folder 14)
      Paula Moore
    - Elfus, Joanna (1993) (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Encuentro de Poetas Chicano Mexicano - Universidad Nacional Autónomo de México (Mexico City) (1986) (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Entelequia (1978-1981) (Box 23, Folder 17)
      Susan Salazar, Chispa Productions
    - Ericksen, Charlie, Hispanic Link Weekly Reporter (1987) (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Estrella, Armando (1979) (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Eureste, Bernardo and Magdalena (1983) (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Evergreen State College, Washington Center for Improving the Quality of Undergraduate Education (1992) (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Evergreen State College (n.d.) (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - La Familia del Paso (1989) (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Farah, Cynthia (1985-1993) (Box 23, Folder 24)
      Writers of the Southwest Project El Paso Public Library
    - Farley, Robbie Jean and John Russell Stanton (1990) (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Favela, Ramon (1990) (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Felix, Rogelio, Trinity OIC of El Paso, Inc. (1972) (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Fenton, Lisa (1987-1988) (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Fernandez, Daniel and Veronica (Box 23, Folder 29.1)
    - Fernandez, Virgil, Aztlan Film Productions (1976) (Box 23, Folder 29.2)
      Rolling Thunder, screen play by Fernandez
    - First Chicano Poetry Festival Organizing Committee (El Paso) (1972) (Box 23, Folder 30)
      Abelardo Delgado Antonio Parra Felipe Ortega
    - Fisher, Tom (n.d.) (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Flores, Gonzalo, Miracle Theater/Teatro Milagro (1992) (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Flores, Lauro (1992) (Box 23, Folder 33)
      University of Washington, Office of the Provost
    - Flores, Noe (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Floricanto V. Committee (1978) (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Ford Foundation (1973-1976) (Box 23, Folder 36)
      Graduate Fellowhips
    - Fortin, Pamela and Frank Sánchez (1992) (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Fortress Church Supply Stores (1983) (Box 23, Folder 38)
      Canto y Grito mi Liberacion
    - Fowler, Gene (1988) (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - Franzen, Norman (1982) (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - Freund, Diane (1988) (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Friaz, Guadalupe (1991-1993) (Box 23, Folder 42)
      National Association for Chicano/a Studies Washington State University
    - Friedman, Susan (1976-1978) (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - Friedman, Susan (n.d.) (Box 23, Folder 44)
    - Friend, Gloria (Le Febre) (1983-1984) (Box 23, Folder 45)
    - Frost, John, American Poetry Anthology (1982) (Box 24, Folder 1)
      "hacky, haspy aspirations" by Sánchez
    - Fryer, Rosemary (1991) (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Galicia, Homero H. (1971-1980) (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Gandara, Nancy (1990) (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - García, Jane (1975) (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - García, Juan (1992) (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - García, Margie (1988) (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Garcia, Theresa, Midwest Canto Al Pueblo (1979) (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Garciaz, Maria (1981) (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Gardea, Reymundo A., M.D. (1975-1982) (Box 24, Folder 10)
      The Paisano Medical Clinic Centro de Salud Familiar La Fe, Inc./La Fe Family Health Center
    - Gardener, Jack (1990) (Box 24, Folder 11)
      Revolutionary Worker
    - Garza, José (1985) (Box 24, Folder 12)
      Casa de Unidad Poetry Anthology Trinidad Sánchez
    - Garza, Marta and Abel (1984) (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Gaucher, R[obert?] (1988) (Box 24, Folder 14)
      criminology department, University of Ottawa
    - Gavin, Glenn (1980-1985) (Box 24, Folder 15)
      Kansas City arts
    - Gaytán, Rey (1990) (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Gelabert, Ana Lucia (1987) (Box 24, Folder 17)
      Medicina y Sociedad (Dec. 1987)
    - Geuder, Pat (1980-1990) (Box 24, Folder 18)
      University of Colorado at Colorado Springs
    - Gilb, Dagoberto (1988-1991) (Box 24, Folder 19)
      Clippings: Sandra Cisneros, Edward James Olmos/"American Me" (article by Gregg Barrios), Amado Maurilo Pena
    - Gi-tar Gutierrez, Johnny (1993) (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Globe Book Company (1992) (Box 24, Folder 21)
      "i yearn" by Sánchez reprinted in Globe Multicultural Anthology for grades 9-12
    - Goldsmith, Andrew (1978-1990, n.d.) (Box 24, Folder 22)
      Adela Iniquez
    - Gómez, José (1992) (Box 24, Folder 23)
      Evergreen State College
    - Gomez, Richard (1988) (Box 24, Folder 24)
      The Echo (prison issues)
    - Gomez, Tino (1991-1993) (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Gonzales, Conrad and Sandra (1990) (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Gonzales, Patricia (1990) (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Gonzalez, Abel (1992) (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Gonzalez, Henry (1987) (Box 24, Folder 29)
      Congress: House of Representatives (20th District, TX) National Endowment for the Arts
    - Gonzales, Herminia (1990) (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Gonzalez, Jorge, Nuevo Santander Museum Complex (Laredo, Texas) (1987) (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Gonzalez, Luis, Hispanic American Society (1979) (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Gonzalez, Marta Iza, Low Rider Magazines (1981) (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - Gonzalez, Patricia (1972-1974, n.d.) (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - Gonzalez, Veronica (1986) (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - Goodell, Larry (1990-1992) (Box 24, Folder 36)
      Duende Press Puerta del Sol Eagle-Visioned/Feathered Adobes (review by Goodell)
    - Goodman, Leonard (1988-1989) (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - Gordan, Roxy (n.d.) (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - Gorski, Hedwig - Fullbright applicant (1982) (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - Gruenbeck, Laurie (1986) (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - Guera, Mary Ann Noonan (n.d.) (Box 24, Folder 41)
      Viva Tejas
    - Guerrero, Andres (1981-1987) (Box 24, Folder 42)
      "A Chicano Theology"
    - Guerrero, Rosa (1975-1990) (Box 24, Folder 43)
      ballet folklorico
    - Guerrero, Zarco (Adolfo) and Carmen de Novais (1976-1989) (Box 24, Folder 44)
    - Guggenheim Foundation (1983) (Box 24, Folder 45)
    - Gutierrez, Jose Angel (1977) (Box 24, Folder 46)
      Narciso Aleman Zavala County, Texas
    - Gutierrez, Margo, Benson Latin American Collection, UT Austin (1987) (Box 24, Folder 47)
      Ricardo Sánchez Collection
    - Gutierrez, Miguel y Maria (1973) (Box 24, Folder 48)
    - Gutierrez y Falcon, Alfredo (1977-1987) (Box 24, Folder 49)
    - Haddox, John (1973-1992, n.d.) (Box 25, Folder 1)
      UT El Paso department of Philosophy ;American Philosophical Society: Committee on International Cooperation ;Michael A. Weinstein ;Octavio Paz ;Fr. Thomas Merton; Prof. Briones ;Border planning issues recommendation for Sánchez
    - Haining, James, Salt Lick Press (1985) (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Hamilton, Terry (1987) (Box 25, Folder 3)
      National Interreligious Task Force on Criminal Justice (NITFCJ); National People Of Color Task Force on Criminal Justice (NPOCTFCJ)
    - Hancock, Joel (1985-1989) (Box 25, Folder 4)
      University of Utah
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich (1988-1990) (Box 25, Folder 5)
      "i yearn" by Sánchez for Chicano Literature anthology for high school students
    - Harjo, Joy (1981) (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Hartman, Johnson (1993, n.d.) (Box 25, Folder 7)
      Sánchez Collections at Stanford and UT Austin
    - Hathaway, James (n.d.) (Box 25, Folder 8)
      UT San Antonio
    - Headley, Mark, Southwestern Film Consortium (n.d.) (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Heidenry, John, Forum International (1988) (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Heidrichstahl, Mellitta (1985) (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Hejinian, Lyn (n.d.) (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Henderson, Bill, Pushcart Press (1977) (Box 25, Folder 13)
      do-it-yourself publishing
    - Henson, Reggie (1983) (Box 25, Folder 14)
      Mah-Nag, Native American Culture Group Newsletter, Palmer, Alaska
    - Hernandez, Alvaro Luna (1987) (Box 25, Folder 15)
      La Resistencia The Crusade for Justice, Rudolfo "Corky" Gonzalez Chicano Prisoners Resistance Movement (CPRM) English Only Simpson-Rodino Allen L. Lamar, O.L. McCotter
    - Hernandez, Lolita (1990) (Box 25, Folder 16)
      Gittin Down: Profiles From Michigan Prison Writers
    - Hernandez, Magdalena and Wayne L. Cuddy (1992) (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Herrera, Jorge (1988) (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Herrero, Gabino Ponce, University of Alicante (Spain) (1991) (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Herring, Marquetta (1988) (Box 25, Folder 20)
      Mesquit eLiterary Festival
    - Hertz Corporation (1986) (Box 25, Folder 21)
      forgery Andrew Ortiz, Lisa McCrury
    - Hetherington, M. Sue (1987) (Box 25, Folder 22)
      Hetherington correspondence includes various clippings, etc.
    - Hetherington, M. Sue (1988) (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Hetherington, M. Sue (1988) (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Hetherington, M. Sue (1988-1989) (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Hetherington, M. Sue (1989) (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Hetherington, M. Sue (1989) (Box 26, Folder 2)
      Hetherington correspondence ncludes various clippings, etc.
    - Hetherington, M. Sue (1989) (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Hetherington, M. Sue (1990) (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Hetherington, M. Sue (1991) (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Hetherington, M. Sue (1992) (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Hetherington, M. Sue (1993) (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Hetherington, M. Sue (n.d.) (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Hetherington, M. Sue (n.d.) (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Hillman, Grady (1981-1987, n.d.) (Box 26, Folder 10)
      Texas Council on Crimne and Delinquency Texas Committee for the Humanities
    - Hinrichs, Max (1979) (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Hinton, Charles (1992) (Box 26, Folder 12)
      American Indian Movement (San Francisco)
    - Hiraoka, Jesse, Journal of Ethnic Studies (1991) (Box 26, Folder 13)
      Western Washington University
    - Hirsch, Dena (1988) (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Hispanic & Business Alliance for Education (1990) (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Hispanic Ministries, Catholic Diocese of Saginaw (1987) (Box 26, Folder 16)
      Andres G. Guerrero, A Chicano Theology Ed. Quentin Hoare, Antonio Gromsci: Selections from Political Writings, "The Young Socialist, 3. Socialism and Culture" (1916)
    - Hobson, Geary (1992) (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Holt, Rinehart and Winston (1991) (Box 26, Folder 18)
      "i yearn" in Mexican American Literature anthology
    - Houghton Mifflin (1974-1975) (Box 26, Folder 19)
      Chicano Voices "to la causa"
    - Houser, John (1988) (Box 26, Folder 20)
      Twelve Travelers project quincentenary (1992) celebration: various organizations descriptions and photographs (copies) of work by Houser
    - Houser, John (1988-1993) (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Houser, John (1988-1991) (Box 27, Folder 1)
      Twelve Travelers project ;quincentenary (1992) celebration: various organizations descriptions and photographs (copies) of work by Houser
    - Houser, John (1991-1993) (Box 27, Folder 2)
      Twelve Travelers project quincentenary (1992) celebration: various organizations descriptions and photographs (copies) of work by Houser "The Gift of Life" prints of paintings by Houser and by Sir Roy Calne
    - Howe, LeAnne (1987) (Box 27, Folder 3)
      "Death on a Stick"
    - Huffstickler, Albert (1983) (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Hummell, Dodie (1985) (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Humphreys, Willard, Evergreen State College (1978) (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Hurd, Don (1988) (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - ICOPA (International Conference on Penal Abolition) (1987) (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Imagine Publishers (1985-1987) (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Indian Rio Grande: Recent Poems from 3 Cultures (anthology) (1981) (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Indiana University, Latino Law Students Association (1980-1981) (Box 27, Folder 11)
      La Raza Legal Alliance Midwest Regional Conference
    - Instituto Cultural Mexicano (n.d.) (Box 27, Folder 12)
      Encuentro de poetas del Mundo Latino (1986) Poetry Tejas International
    - Inter American University Press (1978) (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Intercommunity Center for Justice and Peace (1989-1990) (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Interdenominational Theological Center (1992) (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - International Association for Civilian Oversight of Law Enforcement (1992) (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - International Platform Association (1987) (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Islas, Jovita and Arturo (1991) (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Jackson, Carl (1990) (Box 27, Folder 19)
      UT El Paso, Liberal Arts College 1990 Gold Nugget Award Ceremony, Professor Howard McCord
    - Jackson, Larry, Heidelberg Graphics (1979) (Box 27, Folder 20)
      The Face of Poetry
    - James, Keith (1989) (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Jamison, Susan (1982) (Box 27, Folder 22.1)
    - Jaramillo, Luis (1988) (Box 27, Folder 22.2)
    - Jeantet, Louis (1971-1989) (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Jenifer Jr. High School students (1993) (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Jiménez, Francisco (1981) (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Job Application, "writer" (1981) (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Johnson, Henry (1987) (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - Johnson, Howard George (1988) (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - Albert S. Johnson High School (1982) (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - A.C. Jones High School (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - Jung, Allene Hesskeau (1984) (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - Justice Ministries (1985) (Box 27, Folder 32)
      National People of Color Task Force on Criminal Justice (1985)
    - Kansas Committee for the Humanities (n.d.) (Box 27, Folder 33)
      prison issues, Sánchez project: "Kansas Corrections: What Direction for Prisons? What Choices for Prisoners?"
    - Kay, Stephanie (1991) (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - Keene, Tom (1987-1992) (Box 27, Folder 35)
      "The Colors of Christmas"
    - Keller, Gary, Bilingual Review - Press (1990) (Box 27, Folder 36)
    - Kent, Cynthia, Native American Program Secretary UMC, NY (Box 27, Folder 37)
    - Kern, Stacie (n.d.) (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - Kernahan, Galal (Box 27, Folder 39)
      "El Canto Muere" Magazines of Mexico
    - Kilpatrick, Charles (1987) (Box 27, Folder 40)
    - King, Donna Belmares (1994) (Box 27, Folder 41)
    - KINTV (El Paso), Silvia Parra (1992) (Box 27, Folder 42)
    - Kirkwood, Porter (1984-1990) (Box 27, Folder 43)
      prison issues: James H. Carpenter
    - KLRN Public Television (San Antonio) (1989) (Box 27, Folder 44.1)
    - Koehler, Jesse (1982) (Box 27, Folder 44.2)
    - Kowalewski, David (1984) (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - Kraus, Bill (1980) (Box 27, Folder 46)
    - Kravas, Gus, Vice Provost, Washington State University (1993) (Box 27, Folder 47)
      Marco Antonio Martinez
    - Kuo, Alex (1991), Washington State University (Box 27, Folder 48)
    - Kuzminsky, K. K. (1981-1982) (Box 27, Folder 49)
    - Laguna Gloria Art Museum (Austin, TX) (1977) (Box 27, Folder 50)
      CROSS WORKS
    - Lancaster, Kathy, National Interreligious Task Force on Criminal Justice (1989) (Box 27, Folder 51)
    - Lapointe, Francis (1970) (Box 27, Folder 52)
    - Lara, David (1975-1982) (Box 27, Folder 53)
      "Chicano Poetry" "Mexican-Americans Activism in Political Organizations"
    - Larimer, Anita, Bloomington Community Access Television (n.d.) (Box 27, Folder 54)
    - Latah County Parks and Recreation (1993) (Box 27, Folder 55)
    - Latin Times (Gus Figueroa) (East Chicago, IN) (1970) (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Laufer, Bill (1983) (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Lauritsen, Arthur (1992, n.d.) (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Lawless, Gary, Blackberry (n.d.) (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Lazarin, David (n.d.) (Box 28, Folder 5)
      Media Education Group, "Proposal: Media Action News Service"
    - Lea, Leslie, Queen Anne Press (1985) (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Leal, Luis (1993) (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - LeFebre, Jauquin, Canto al Pueblo (1979) (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Lejia, Luis Enrique (1985) (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - LeRoy, Lewis (1988) (Box 28, Folder 10.1)
      El Paso Herald Post column "hate mail"
    - Levine, Ellen, Literary Agency, Inc. (1990) (Box 28, Folder 10.2)
    - Lewis, Rob (1983-1994) (Box 28, Folder 11)
      The Human Condition (1990-1991)
    - Lewis, Rob, publisher: correspondence relating to Amerikan Journeys::Jornadas Americanas, original folders 1/5 and 2/5 (1994) (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Lewis, Rob, publisher: correspondence relating to Amerikan Journeys::Jornadas Americanas, original folders 3/5 and 5/5 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Lewis, Rob, publisher: correspondence relating to Amerikan Journeys::Jornadas Americanas, original folder 5/5: PROOFS (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Lewiston Morning Tribune (1992) (Box 28, Folder 15)
      Cinco de Mayo article
    - Liberté, Inc. (1988) (Box 28, Folder 16)
      "Creativity Can't be Imprisoned" San Antonio Express News 1/31/88
    - Lightbourn-Harbeck, Margarita (1989) (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Littlebird, Harold (1986) (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Lizalde, Eduardo (1986-1987) (Box 28, Folder 19)
      Direccion General de Publicaciones y Medios, Mexico D.F. proposal for book: Canto Tejano: Voceros de la Poesía Chicana Movimientista
    - Lomelí, Francisco (1975-1983) (Box 28, Folder 20)
      "El Concepto del barrio en tres poetas chicanos: Abelardo, Alurista y Ricardo Sánchez"
    - Lomelí, Francisco (1983-1994) (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Long, Jo, The Carver Community Culteral Center (1991) (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - Lopez, Emy (1980) (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - Lopez, Josefina (1982) (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - Lopez, Miguel R. (1993) (Box 28, Folder 25)
      John Pierce
    - Lopez, Roy (1988-1991) (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - Lopez-Portillo, Carmen R. de (1981) (Box 28, Folder 27)
      first lady of Mexico
    - Lowenfels, Walter (1972) (Box 28, Folder 28)
      From the Belly of the Shark
    - Luján, Ken, Colorado Migrant Council (1972) (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - Lynch, Peggy Zuleika and Edmund (1984-1988) (Box 28, Folder 30)
      Poetry and the Arts
    - Mac, Mary (1981) (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - MacArthur, Mary, Gallimaufry (1976) (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - Magi Productions (1990) (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - Maldonado, Antonio (1987) (Box 28, Folder 34)
    - Maldonado, Carolyn, English Only Movement (1984) (Box 28, Folder 35)
    - Mann, Coramae Richey (1993) (Box 28, Folder 36)
    - Mann, Dana (1987-1990) (Box 28, Folder 37)
    - Marble, Guy (1988) (Box 28, Folder 38)
      Editor, The Echo prison issues
    - Marcus, Hal (1990-1991) (Box 28, Folder 39)
      Chuck Taylor Gene Keller Sánchez 25th anniversary photos
    - Mares, Andres (1992) (Box 28, Folder 40)
    - Mares, E. A. "Tony" (1986-1989) (Box 28, Folder 41)
    - Markus, Danny, Latah County Parks and Recreation (1992) (Box 29, Folder 1)
      photos
    - Márquez, María Teresa (1988-1991, n.d.) (Box 29, Folder 2)
      New Mexico State University
    - Márquez, Teresa (1987) (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Martín-Rodriguez, Manuel M. (1990-1992) (Box 29, Folder 4)
      La Voz urgente: Antología de literatura chicana en español "Oye, Pito: Esta es la vida bruta de un boy." Yale department of Spanish and Portuguese
    - Martínez, Armando Moisés (1990) (Box 29, Folder 5)
      New Visions of Aztlán California Democratic Perty: Chicano Latino Caucus
    - Martínez, Ernesto P. (1973-1981) (Box 29, Folder 6)
      "Thought to the Art of Ernesto Martinez" and other poems to Martínez by Sánchez
    - Martínez, Lee (1982) (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Martinez, Solomón (1980) (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Martinez, Vicente (1992) (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Martínez, Walter, City Council of San Antonio (1986) (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - The Suzanne McAlister Show (1990) (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - McArthur, Mary (1981) (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - McClellan, Tom, The Texas Observer (Austin) (1989) (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - McCullough, Frances (1979) (Box 29, Folder 14)
      Harper & Row; National Endowment for the Arts
    - McDonald, Kathryn Stewart (1991) (Box 29, Folder 15)
      Vision Quest, Stevan Publications
    - McFarland, Ron, University of Idaho (1992) (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - McGraw-Hill Book Company (1981) (Box 29, Folder 17)
      "i yearn"
      Focus: Themes in Literature
    - McKenzie, Phyllis (1986) (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - McLemee, Scott (1983) (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - McNab, Terry (1988) (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - MEChA, Voz de Aztlán (newsletter) (1992) (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Medina, Felipe (family of) (1992) (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Medina, Javier (1991-1992) (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Medrano, Manuel (1982) (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - Melendez, Hilda, Linda and Johnny (1989) (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Mexican-American Chamber of Congress, Travis County, TX (1983) (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - Mexican-American Cultural Center (San Antonio) (1984) (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - Mexicana Airlines Lost and Found Department (1986) (Box 29, Folder 28)
      lost baggage
    - MexicArte (1984) (Box 29, Folder 29)
      Dia de los Muertos, "La Muerte Vive"
    - Michel, Elinor (1994) (Box 29, Folder 30)
      University of Idaho
    - MIDIA comunicacion (1986) (Box 29, Folder 31)
    - Miller, Tom (1989) (Box 29, Folder 32)
      On the Border "desde el barrio" -"from the tenement"
    - "Minority Arts: A New Direction" (1985) (Box 29, Folder 33)
      Corpus Christi Arts Council -Multicultural Center; Ted Shine ;Francisco Fajardo Myrna Renaud ;Betty Switzer ;John Paul Batiste ;Ricardo Hernandez ;George Cisneros
    - Mojica, Rafael (1992-1993) (Box 29, Folder 34)
      poetry
    - Moncada, Alberto, Instituto de Cooperacion Iberomericano (1989) (Box 29, Folder 35)
    - Monchi, (?), South West Training Institute (1979) (Box 29, Folder 36)
    - Monson, Michael (n.d.) (Box 29, Folder 37)
      "Hispanic Activist Turns Literary Prof" article in WSU Evergreen
    - Montalvo, Jose (1982) (Box 29, Folder 38)
      Chicano Literature Project, P.A.N., San Antonio
    - Montejano, Diana R. (1988-1992) (Box 29, Folder 39)
    - Montoya, Jose, and RCAF (1974-1979, n.d.) (Box 29, Folder 40)
      RAYAS: Newsletter of Chicano Arts and Literature (Mar-April 1979, No. 2)
    - Montoya, Vicenta (1983) (Box 29, Folder 41)
    - Morales, Travis (1992) (Box 29, Folder 42)
      Abimael Guzmán, aka Chairman Gonzalo, Communist Party of Peru
    - Moramarco, Fred and Al Zolynas (1989) (Box 29, Folder 43)
      Heartstories: An Anthology of Poetry by Contemporary American Men
    - Moreno, Jimmy (1988-1989) (Box 29, Folder 44)
    - Moreno, Jose (1985) (Box 29, Folder 45)
    - Morgan, Alexander (1985) (Box 29, Folder 46)
    - Morgan, J. A., Attorney at Law (1979) (Box 29, Folder 47)
      Grayhound accident involving Mr. and Mrs. Manuel Silva
    - Morrison, Morris (1983) (Box 29, Folder 48)
    - Morton, Carlos (1984-1988) (Box 29, Folder 49)
      "Pancho Diablo"
    - Moscow Renaissance Fair (1991-1992) (Box 29, Folder 50)
    - Muniz, Ramiro Ramsey (1980) (Box 29, Folder 51)
      La Raza Unida
    - Munoz, Rodolfo (1993) (Box 29, Folder 52)
      prison issues: Frank N. Cervantes vs. Texas Department of Corrections government conspiracy
    - Munoz, Rodolfo (1993) (Box 29, Folder 53)
      prison issues: Frank N. Cervantes vs. Texas Department of Corrections government conspiracy National Movement of La Raza
    - Munoz, Rodolfo (1993-1994 ) (Box 29, Folder 54)